Guide to the Julius Hemphill Papers MSS.542
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Long Tongues: A Saxophone Opera - Assorted photocopies of score, 1985-1990; cuid20616 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  Assorted photocopies of full score (holograph and conductor's score) for "Long Tongues: A Saxophone Opera," some with annotations in various hands.
- Long Tongues: A Saxophone Opera - Holograph and Conductor's Score, 1985-1990; cuid20617 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  Holograph full score, in pencil and blue, black, and red ink. Conductor's score (oversize), cleanly copied in pencil, with annotations in black and red ink by unknown hand. Individual sections include "Georgia Blue," "Band Theme," "Danse A La Midi," "A Prayer Type Line," "Sketch I," "Sketch II," "Sketch III," "Sketch IV," "Overture," "Bop Scene: KC Line," "Otis' Groove," "Mask Dance," "R and B," "Dogon A.D.," "For Andrew," "Soulo."
- Papers and Ephemera, 1938-1995; cuid20618 (Box 6)
  Letters, play scripts, interview transcripts, promotional material, Hemphill's undergraduate diploma, audiocassette tape shells with inserts (to be retained), and other ephemera.
- Papers and Ephemera, 1938-1995; cuid20619 (Box 16)
- Foran Notebook, 1968-1995; cuid20620 (Box 7)
  Foran brand manuscript notebook with hand-written title "A guide to the reckless conservatism of musical notation as expressed via M. Boyé."
- Kawaida Notebook, 1968-1995; cuid20621 (Box 7)
  Sightation brand manuscript notebook, with "Kawaida contd" and "Hemphill" written on cover.
- Chiaroscuro Notebook, 1968-1995; cuid20622 (Box 7)
  Pasantino brand manuscript notebook, with "Chiaroscuro" written on cover, along with "Roi Boyé" and several addresses.
- Schirmer's Notebook, 1968-1995; cuid20623 (Box 7)
  Schirmer's brand manuscript notebook, with "Portland Orego" and Hemphill's name and address written on cover.
- Sightation Notebook, 1968-1995; cuid20624 (Box 7)
  Sightation brand manuscript notebook, lacking covers.
- Musik Hug Notebook, 1968-1995; cuid20625 (Box 7)
  Musik Hug brand manuscript notebook with several addresses and phone numbers written on cover.
- Trumpet Notebook, 1968-1995; cuid20626 (Box 7)
  Archives brand manuscript notebook with trumpet parts
- Bass Notebook, 1968-1995; cuid20627 (Box 7)
  Archives brand manuscript notebook with bass parts
- Drums Notebook, 1968-1995; cuid20628 (Box 7)
  Archives brand manuscript notebook with drum parts
- "A Bitter Glory" Notebook - Alto sax, 1993-1995; cuid20629 (Box 7)
  Citadel brand manuscript notebook with "Alto Sax, Sopran Sax, Flute" on cover. Several loose pages with poetry.
- "A Bitter Glory" Notebook - Cello, 1993-1995; cuid20630 (Box 7)
  Citadel brand manuscript notebook with "Cello" written on cover.
- "A Bitter Glory" Notebook - [Baritone Saxophone, Flute, Clarinet], 1993-1995; cuid20631 (Box 7)
  Citadel brand manuscript notebook with "bari sax / fl / clar " written faintly on cover. Includes clarinet parts.
- "A Bitter Glory" Notebook - Trumpet, 1993-1995; cuid20632 (Box 7)
  Citadel brand manuscript notebook with "Trumpet" written on cover.
- "A Bitter Glory" Notebook - French Horn, 1993-1995; cuid20633 (Box 7)
  Citadel brand manuscript notebook with "French Horn" written on cover.
- "A Bitter Glory" Notebook - Trombone, 1993-1995; cuid20634 (Box 7)
  Citadel brand manuscript notebook with "Trombone" written on cover.
- "A Bitter Glory" Notebook - Bass, 1993-1995; cuid20635 (Box 7)
  Citadel brand manuscript notebook with "Bass" written on cover.
- Julius Hemphill Sextet Collection Notebooks, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 1-6)
- Julius Hemphill Sextet Collection Folios, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 1-6)
- Julius Hemphill Boye' Multi National Crusade for Harmony (2 of 2), 1979-1995; cuid20637 (Box 9, Audiocassette 2)
  D.C. Space, Washington, D.C., Nov 23, 1979 Julius Hemphill (tenor sax, alto sax); Baikida Carroll (trumpet); Jehri Riley (guitar); Phillip Wilson (drums) Cassette 2 0f 2 Audiocassette Sony LNX 60
- Julius Hemphill Boye' Multi National Crusade for Harmony (1A of 2), 1979-1995; cuid20638 (Box 9, Audiocassette 2A)
  D.C. Space, Washington D. C., Nov 23, 1979 Julius Hemphill (tenor sax, alto sax); Baikida Carroll (trumpet); Jehri Riley (guitar); Phillip Wilson (drums) Cassette 1A 0f 2 Audiocassette Sony LNX 60
- Julis HEMPHILL (1), 1980-1995; cuid20639 (Box 9, Audiocassette 3)
  Julius Hemphill - sax tenor, alto, sop; Olu Dara - trompette; Abdul Wadud - violoncelle; Warren Smith - batterie Toulouse 12-06-80 Audiocassette TDK D90 type 1
- Julius Hemphill Trio - Public Theater, New York City, December 19, 1981; cuid20640 (Box 9, Audiocassette 4)
  Featuring Julius Hemphill (alto saxophone, soprano saxophone and flute), Jamaladeen Tacuma (electric bass), and Michael Carvin (drums). Recorded by Kazunori Sugiyama
- Julius Hemphill Trio - Public Theater, New York City, December 19, 1981; cuid20724 (Box 9, Audiocassette 91)
- May 19, 1987 - Rollins Chapel, 1987-1995; cuid20641 (Box 9, Audiocassette 6)
  No one knows a garden better than the gardener, a follower should always allow their guide to lead Julius Hemphill; Abdul Wadud; Warren Smith; Bill Cole Rollins Chapel, 5-19-87 Audiocassette Maxell C90
- COOL RED 5/22/87, 1987-1995; cuid20642 (Box 9, Audiocassette 7)
  World Saxophone Quartet Cool Red, 5/22/87 Audiocassette TDK SA60 with Dolby [Probably a set of takes from the recording session; may differ from commercial release]
- SWEET D - LEORA, 1987-1995; cuid20643 (Box 9, Audiocassette 8)
  [Sweet D - Leora written in Hemphill's hand] Audiocassette TDK SA60
- Imp Ork #1 - June 2, 1990, 1990-1995; cuid20644 (Box 9, Audiocassette 9)
  Imp Ork @ WAC June 2, 1990 tape #1 of 2 Audiocassette Dub Norm/Dolby B
- WPFW Interview, 1987-1995; cuid20645 (Box 9, Audiocassette 10)
  2 February 1987 Audiocassette Laser 90 low noise
- Julius Hemphill Quintet - Live at Kimball's S.F. 3-17-84, 1984-1995; cuid20646 (Box 9, Audiocassette 11)
  Julius Hemphill - alto and soprano sax; Nels Cline- elec guitar; Stubig - bass guitar; Alex Cline - drums; Juma Santos - congas, perc. All compositions by Julius Hemphill; copies by Chris Hemphill (son) Recorded at Kinball's S.F., March 17 1984 Side I: 1. Dung; 2. Dogon A.D.; 3. Testament #5; 4. Float (head and alto solo) Side 2: 1. Pigskin; 2. Border Town (reiteration of head, cut off on original tape; 3. At Harmony Audiocassette BASF Performance I 90
- Jazz Monthly Magazine - Julius Hemphill Audio Profile, 1987-1995; cuid20647 (Box 9, Audiocassette 12)
  Jazz Monthly Magazine - Julius Hemphill Audio Profile May 87 Excerpt - Side 1 only Audiocassette
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Preservation note: Side 2 has intermittent sound and silence, as though it had been partially erased.
- Jack DeJohnette UCLA, 1986-1995; cuid20648 (Box 9, Audiocassette 13)
  Jack DeJohnette Jazz Machine Concert - Arrangements Julius Hemphill UCLA 4/27/86 1. Ebony 2. Ahmad the Terrible Audiocassette TDK SA 90
  Preservation Note: Some crackle.
- WATER MUSIC FOR WOODWINDS 10/3/77, 1977-1995; cuid20649 (Box 9, Audiocassette 14)
  [Composed by Julius Hemphill] 10/3/77 Audiocassette TDK SA90
- Hemphill on KWMU 6-30-87, 1987-1995; cuid20650 (Box 9, Audiocassette 15)
  [Sheldon Auditorium, St. Louis, MO], 6-30-87 Jim Wallace of KWMU, St. Louis reports on Julius Hemphill's performance at the Sheldon (5:00) Audiocassette BASF LH-EI 60
- LONG TONGUES Parts I and II, 1976-1995; cuid20651 (Box 9, Audiocassette 16)
  LONG TONGUES (7/20) Part I; L.T. Part II (Lincoln Center) Audiocassette Maxwell UR 90
- LUSH LIFE WSQ, 1976-1995; cuid20652 (Box 9, Audiocassette 17)
  Lush Life WSQ [written in Hemphill's hand] Audiocassette TDK SA90
- Big Bands/Jazz on the Edge TAPE 1/21, 1976-1995; cuid20653 (Box 9, Audiocassette 18)
  WGBH radio Boston producer - Robert Lyons Side 1: Orange Then Blue (ensemble); Ahmad The Terrible; Kookoo; Panama Side Two: OTB/Either Orchestra Audiocassette [Ahmad the Terrible is the Hemphill arrangement of a Jack DeJohnette composition and is the only Hemphill work on this broadcast.]
- SFCMF - Hemphill: Parchment, 1976-1995; cuid20654 (Box 9, Audiocassette 19)
  SFCMF - Hemphill: Parchment [Ursula] Oppens- piano Audiocassette TDK AD60
- ELLINGTON CONCERT Part I, 1976-1995; cuid20655 (Box 9, Audiocassette 20)
  Side A - [Oliver] Lake Side B - Hemphill Audiocassette
- Julius HEMPHILL (2), 1980-1995; cuid20656 (Box 9, Audiocassette 21)
  Toulouse, 12-6-80 Julius Hemphill; Olu Dara; Abdul Wadud; Warren Smith Audiocassette TDK D90
- Julius / Messin with the Kid; Lets Get it On, 1976-1995; cuid20657 (Box 9, Audiocassette 22)
  Audiocassette Maxell XL11-S 90
- JAH Band Live at Weil Hall NYC 3/23/87 Pt. 1 and 3, 1987-1995; cuid20658 (Box 9, Audiocassette 23)
  Weil/Carnagie Hall, 3/27/87 Rasul Siddik; John Stubblefield; John Clark; Alan Jaffe; Mark Helias; Gordon Gotlieb [all spellings as written in Hemphill's hand] Audiocassette Maxell XL1190
- JAH Band Live at Weill Hall NYC 3/23/87 SIDE 2 and 4, 1987-1995; cuid20659 (Box 9, Audiocassette 24)
  Side A: Weill Recital Hall 3/27/87 8PM #2 Side B: #4 3) ""Sweet D"" (0-366); 4) ""At Harmony"" (386-620); 5) (630) Gottlieb; 6) ""Georgia Blue"" Audiocassette Maxell XL 11 90 with noise reduction
- Ursula Oppens and The Arditti String Qt. - Tape #1 of 2, 1992-1995; cuid20660 (Box 9, Audiocassette 25)
  [Hemphill, ""One Atmosphere,"" for piano and string quartet] 27 February 92 Audiocassette WNYC Dolby B Chrome Cassette side A and B
- Ursula Oppens and The Arditti String Qt. -Tape #2 of 2, 1992-1995; cuid20661 (Box 9, Audiocassette 26)
- Monk - Darrell Katz True Colors Big Band, 1976-1995; cuid20662 (Box 9, Audiocassette 27)
  Audiocassette Maxell XLII 60 [May include a Hemphill composition or Hemphill as soloist.]
- Hemphill Pt. 1 - Gran(?) Rehearsal, 1976-1995; cuid20663 (Box 9, Audiocassette 28)
  Wadud; Baikida; Marty Ehrlich Side 1. -Pt. 2 - Cami Hall Sept. 23 Side 2 - Hemphill- Cami Hall Sept.5 Audiocassette Memorex 90 MRX3 Oxide [no shell]
- REHEARSAL LENOX [on cassette], 1976-1995; cuid20664 (Box 9, Audiocassette 29)
  Side A - Dialogue: Blk/Blue Side B - Rehearsal Lenox Audiocassette TDK - D-C60
- 170 Sax [on cassette], 1976-1995; cuid20665 (Box 9, Audiocassette 30)
  [No title] Side A -1 - 170 Sax Side B -2 Audiocassette Maxell UD 60 Normal Position
- WSQ II, 1976-1995; cuid20666 (Box 9, Audiocassette 31)
  Night Train 47 Ballad and Tag 50 Audiocassette TDK SA60
- Julius Hemphill 5/31/85 [1 of 2], 1985-1995; cuid20667 (Box 9, Audiocassette 32)
  5/31/85 Audiocassette maxell XLII 90
- Julius Hemphill 5-31-85 [2 of 2], 1985-1995; cuid20668 (Box 9, Audiocassette 33)
  5-31-85 Audiocassette maxell XLII 90
- HEMPHILL and JAFFE CLARK; WADUD; CARROLL - BOSTON TAPE 2, 1985-1995; cuid20669 (Box 9, Audiocassette 34)
  Hemphill Boston 9/27/85 #2 with Clark Wadud Carroll Jaffe Audiocassette Maxell XLII 90
- HEMPHILL and JAFFE CLARK; WADUD; CARROLL - BOSTON #1, 1985-1995; cuid20670 (Box 9, Audiocassette 35)
  Hemphill Boston 9/27/85 #1 with Clark Wadud Carroll Jaffe Audiocassette Maxell XLII 90
- JAH-BAND, 1976-1995; cuid20671 (Box 9, Audiocassette 36)
  Jah- Band 1 and 3 Audiocassette Maxell XL90 with Dolby B
- Hemphill Quartet Live at Ft. Washington Men's Shelter, 1986-1995; cuid20672 (Box 9, Audiocassette 37)
  1/21/86 Audiocassette Maxell XLII90
- Julius Hemphill with the Barbary Coast Jazz Ensemble, 1986-1995; cuid20673 (Box 9, Audiocassette 38)
  Hemphill with the Barbary Coast Jazz Ensemble-directed by Don Glasgo Spaulding Aud., Dartmouth College, Hanover N.H., Feb.8th 1986 1. C (those Blues; 2. Border Town; 3. At Harmony; 4. Hard Blues Audiocassette Maxell C90 - Communicator Series
- Practice JAH 2 1/2 "Ch" Vandoren, 1976-1995; cuid20674 (Box 9, Audiocassette 39)
  Audiocassette Maxell SLII90
- Sessions 2/22/88 Takes 15-27, 28-36, 1988-1995; cuid20675 (Box 9, Audiocassette 40)
  Nonesuch Audiocassette TDK SA90 Dolby
- Circles [on cassette], 1976-1995; cuid20676 (Box 9, Audiocassette 42)
  [Annotation in felt pen written over ""Smokey Robinson and the Miricles, Goin in Circles/Ojays] Audiocassette Aiwa c-60LX
- St. Louis w/D. Hines [David Hines] Sheldon Memorial, 1976-1995; cuid20677 (Box 9, Audiocassette 43)
  [Sheldon Memorial Concert Hall, St. Louis, MO] Audiocassette TDK SA90
- World Saxophone Quartet I [on cassette], 1976-1995; cuid20678 (Box 9, Audiocassette 44)
  Audiocassette TDK SA90
- SESSION COPY, 1988-1995; cuid20679 (Box 9, Audiocassette 46)
  Session Copy RCA (studio) 2/21-22/88 NYC BTown At Harmony For Billie / Drunk on God Leora [Probably a set of takes from the recording session; may differ from commercial release] Audiocassette
- Long Tongues (Rehearsal?), 1976-1995; cuid20680 (Box 9, Audiocassette 47)
  Audiocassette Maxell XLII 90
- Proverb Work tape for Julius Hemphill, 1976-1995; cuid20681 (Box 9, Audiocassette 48)
  He who Beats A Drum for a Madman to Panel... A Scan (?) Its Never as Smooth as natural Skin Audiocassette Maxell C60
- JAH, 1976-1995; cuid20682 (Box 9, Audiocassette 49)
  [JAH band] Side A: JAH Side B: JAH Audiocassette Maxell XLII 90
- JAH-BAND, 1976-1995; cuid20683 (Box 9, Audiocassette 50)
  JAH-BAND 2 B [Dolby B] JAH-BAND 4 B [Dolby B] Audiocassette maxell XLII 90
- Julius edited copy Anchorman, 1976-1995; cuid20684 (Box 9, Audiocassette 51)
  Julius edited copy Anchorman Audiocassette
- Brucker Hall Concert [Insert: The United States Army Band; Washington D.C.; Colonel Eugene W. Allen, Leader and Commander], 1976-1995; cuid20685 (Box 9, Audiocassette 52)
  Savoy D Beard Producer and Director Audiocassette Ampex 90
- JAH - Mar 15, 1986 - Hoffhei, 1986-1995; cuid20686 (Box 9, Audiocassette 53)
  Side A - Dung; The Thang; Temporarily; One Waltz Side B - Testament; Dogon; Georgia Blue; Hard Blues(inc) Hemphill, Alex Cline, Nels Cline, Steubig, Allan Jaffe Audiocassette Maxell UD I 90
- J.A.H. Band Willisau - 8-31-84 (1 of 3), 1984-1995; cuid20687 (Box 9, Audiocassette 54)
  Julius Hemphill's JAH Band (cassette 1 of 3) Willisau, Switzerland; Aug. 31, 1984 Julius Hemphill (alto sax, tenor sax); Nels Cline (guitar); Steuart Liebig (bass) Alex Cline (drums); Jumma Santos (percussion) Audiocassette TDK D60
- J.A.H. Band Willisau - 8-31-84 (2 of 3), 1984-1995; cuid20688 (Box 9, Audiocassette 55)
  Julius Hemphill's JAH Band (cassette 2 of 3) Willisau, Switzerland; Aug. 31, 1984 Julius Hemphill (alto sax, tenor sax); Nels Cline (guitar); Steuart Liebig (bass) Alex Cline (drums); Jumma Santos (percussion) Audiocassette TDK D60
- J.A.H. Band Willisau - 8-31-84 (3 of 3), 1984-1995; cuid20689 (Box 9, Audiocassette 56)
  Julius Hemphill's JAH Band (cassette 3 of 3) Willisau, Switzerland; Aug. 31, 1984 Julius Hemphill (alto sax, tenor sax); Nels Cline (guitar); Steuart Liebig (bass) Alex Cline (drums); Jumma Santos (percussion) Audiocassette TDK D60
- The JAH Band, 1976-1995; cuid20690 (Box 9, Audiocassette 57)
  Georgia Blue; The Hard Blues; Testament #5 Audiocassette Maxell XL II90
  Preservation Note: Second side very quiet on left audio track.
- Boye Multi National Crusade For Harmony CASA, St. Louis, 1976-1995; cuid20691 (Box 9, Audiocassette 58)
  Audiocassette Maxell UDXLII C90
- Hemphill, Wadud - Sept. 27, 81 - CAMI Hall NY, 1981-1995; cuid20692 (Box 9, Audiocassette 59)
  CAMI Hall, NY; Sun. Sept.27, 1981 Audiocassette TDK D-C90
- PRACTICE, 1976-1995; cuid20693 (Box 9, Audiocassette 60)
  Practice Audiocassette TDK D-C60
- Live in N.Y.- La Mama Theatre, 1976-1995; cuid20694 (Box 9, Audiocassette 61)
  Abdul Wadud/Solo [Side 1] 1) 7'; 2) 5'; 3) 7'; 4) 5 [Side 2] 1); 2); 3)
- World Saxophone Quartet - Detroit Institute of Arts; 11/7/82, 1982-1995; cuid20695 (Box 9, Audiocassette 62)
  1 of 2 Audiocassette Cr O2 Dolby
- Gongs @ Zinnegers Oregon, 1976-1995; cuid20696 (Box 9, Audiocassette 63)
  Audiocassette MAXELL UD C60
  Preservation Note: Side 1 recorded only on one track. Side 2 has some recorded-in distortion, slowing down, backing up, etc.
- 1st Session; Ad Lib, 1976-1995; cuid20697 (Box 9, Audiocassette 64)
  [no shell] Audiocassette Maxell C-90
- J. Hemphill - A. Wadud, 1976-1995; cuid20698 (Box 9, Audiocassette 65)
  [Side A] Syntax 9.01; Tightenin' 9.55; Slang 9.50 [Side B] Untitled 10.04; Rhapsody 10.32; Downstairs 10.13 Audiocassette D-C60 TDK
- Wadud Solo CAMI Hall, 1981-1995; cuid20699 (Box 9, Audiocassette 66)
  Sun Sept. 27, 81 Audiocassette TDK D-C90
- J. Hemphill Workshop #1 + Jam session - Mil. Museum of Fine Arts; 21 Oct. 81, 1981-1995; cuid20700 (Box 9, Audiocassette 67)
  21 Oct '81 (0 to 150) Jam Session; 10 Bar Blues; ""After Eight"" (151-366) Audiocassette TDK SA-C90
- J. Hemphill - A. Wadud, 1976-1995; cuid20701 (Box 9, Audiocassette 68)
  Live 19:00; 16:40 Audiocassette TDK D-C60
- Master WSQ '80 Paris, 1980-1995; cuid20702 (Box 9, Audiocassette 69)
  IRCAM; '80 [Side 1] 1. Revue (slow); 2. Revue (slower); 3. Slide; 4. Hymn for Old Year; 5. [Hymn for Old Year]; 6. Ming; 7. Davids tune (med.); 8. David's tune incomplete slow [Side 2] 1. David's tune; 2. Ming; 3. Played Once; 4. Played Twice; 5. I Heard that; 6. Functions; 7. Little Samba; 8. Affairs of the Heart; 9.; 10. TDK SA C-90 Audiocassette Complete Studio Date; Mono
- Concert Seattle Julius Hemphill, 1983-1995; cuid20703 (Box 9, Audiocassette 70)
  Seattle; 1983 Bordertown Seattle J. Hemphill Audiocassette Sony UCX-90
- 3 [on cassette], 1976-1995; cuid20704 (Box 9, Audiocassette 71)
  [Side A] 3 [Side B] 4 Audiocassette Maxell UD 60
- World Saxophone Quartet at Avery Fisher; 6-29-82, 1982-1995; cuid20705 (Box 9, Audiocassette 72)
  Audiocassette TDK AD-C60
- Julius Hemphill at CMS-10/21/78, 1978-1995; cuid20706 (Box 9, Audiocassette 73)
  [Side 1] Julius Hemphil - sax, fl; Marilyn Crisbell - piano; Janet Grice - bassoon; Marty Ehrlich - alto, b. clar., fl; Baikida Carroll - tr. Flug Side Two exclude piano Audiocassette Ampex 90 Recorded by Mark Kramer
  Preservation Note: Pressure pad detached -- reattached. Tape extremely sticky. Incubated, still would not transport. Reshelled into a new cassette, transferred but with substantial distortion. Incubated a second time, transferred successfully, though with some tape squeal which occasionally carries through to recording as noise.
- Julius Hemphill w/ CM Student Orch - 10/20/78, 1978-1995; cuid20707 (Box 9, Audiocassette 74)
  Audiocassette Ampex 90
- World Saxophone Quartet, 1976-1995; cuid20708 (Box 9, Audiocassette 75)
  [Side A] Sundance; Plain Song; Connections; WSQ [Side B] Pillars Latino; Suite: The Key, Pam-Ma, Ballad for Eddie Jefferson, Hattie Wall; Sound Light; Fast Life Audiocassette Maxell C60
- ACME #2, 1976-1995; cuid20709 (Box 9, Audiocassette 76)
  [No shell] Audiocassette TDK C60
- The World Saxophone Quartet on NPR's ""All Things Considered"" [on cassette; container has 'For July 8th Concert], 1976-1995; cuid20710 (Box 9, Audiocassette 77)
  Audiocassette TDK AD-C60 [Container and cassette have different information]
- Julius Hemphill Workshop - MIL, 1981-1995; cuid20711 (Box 9, Audiocassette 78)
  [Side A] 23-10-81 [Side B] 26-10-81 Audiocassette TDK SA-C90
- Save! Save!, 1976-1995; cuid20712 (Box 9, Audiocassette 79)
  [no shell] Audiocassette TDK SA-C90
- Ralph Ellison Long Tonge, 1976-1995; cuid20713 (Box 9, Audiocassette 80)
  Bells [Side A] Tape #1 - A [Side B] Tape 1 - B Audiocassette Sony C-90
- Tape 2 - Voice, 1976-1995; cuid20714 (Box 9, Audiocassette 81)
  Audiocassette Sony C-90
- Jazz Monthly Magazine w/ Julius Hemphill Profile, 1976-1995; cuid20715 (Box 9, Audiocassette 82)
  Side I cut Ends w/ D. Gonzalez JMM, cont'd on Side II Audiocassette
- Robert Johnson and his Chillun', 1976-1995; cuid20716 (Box 9, Audiocassette 83)
  [No shell] B/HX Audiocassette TDK D-90
- Julius Hemphill 12 pc. Orch, 1980-1995; cuid20717 (Box 9, Audiocassette 84)
  [No shell] Public Theatre; Nov 1st, 80 [Side A] (Set 1) [Side B] Julius's Band (cont) (Set 1) Audiocassette Sony LNX-90
- Julius Hemphill 12 pc. Orch, 1976-1995; cuid20718 (Box 9, Audiocassette 85)
  [No shell] Dolphy Clothes Love Audiocassette Ampex EDR-60
  Preservation Note: Pressure pad missing -- replaced. Intractibly sticky near head -- consequently did not capture beginning of Side 1 (except for very first seconds -- saved as a separate file) & end of Side 2. Remainder of tape captured with some distortion. Baked again, captured in its entirety with some distortion.
- K. Curtis Lyle Reading His Poem "Sylvester St. Elmo Hope Delivers His Sermon in St. James For the Last Time This Morning and Disappears in an Easter Sunrise", 1976-1995; cuid20719 (Box 9, Audiocassette 86)
  [No shell] [No information] Audiocassette Scotch AVC 60min
- Kool Newport Jazz Festival: The New Music Meets the Old Master, Performance and Rehearsal, Circa June 1980; cuid20720 (Box 9, Audiocassette 87)
  [No shell] [No information] Audiocassette TDK AD-C90; Featuring Oliver Lake, Julius Hemphill, Muhal Richard Abrams, and Leroy Jenkins; Rehearsal songs include "I Got It Bad and That Ain't Good" by Duke Ellington, arranged by Hemphill, and "In a Sentimental Mood" by Duke Ellington, arranged by Oliver Lake.
- Julius Hemphill and Peter Kowald Live Performance, 1976-1995; cuid20721 (Box 9, Audiocassette 88)
  [No information] Audiocassette Fuji FR-II 90
- Radio advertisement for Bloomingdales, 1976-1995; cuid20722 (Box 9, Audiocassette 89)
  [No shell] [No information] Audiocassette Maxell XLII 90
- Blue Boyé, 1977; cuid20723 (Box 9, Audiocassette 90)
  [No information] Audiocassette TDK SD-C90
- Julius Hemphill Trio Rehearsal, including "Pigskin," "At Harmony," and "Dogon, A.D.", 1976-1995; cuid20725 (Box 9, Audiocassette 92)
  Possibly Gerard Veasley on bass and Mike Clark on drums, with writer Chip Stern.
- KUSC Interview with Pianist Ursula Oppens, Los Angeles, 1976-1995; cuid20726 (Box 9, Audiocassette 93)
  [No information] Audiocassette
- Work Tape, 1976-1995; cuid20727 (Box 9, Audiocassette 94)
  [No shell] Work Tape Audiocassette Maxell Communicator Series P/I C60
- Julius Hemphill's Answering Machine, 1976-1995; cuid20728 (Box 9, Audiocassette 95)
  Audiocassette Sanyo Announcement Cassette
- Phone Mate, 1976-1995; cuid20729 (Box 9, Audiocassette 96)
  [No shell] Audiocassette Phone Mate Incoming Message Tape C-60
- Wind and Thunder at Babson College -, 1987-1995; cuid20730 (Box 9, Audiocassette 101)
  Second half of program Babson College; 2-26-87 Bill Cole; Julius Hemphill; Gerald Veasley; Hafiz Shabazz Audiocassette Maxell Communicator Series C90
- New Tango '92: After Astor Piazzolla (Or, The Second Assassin), 1992-1995; cuid20731 (Box 9, Audiocassette 102)
  [Rare commercial release; additional information on printed insert] Audiocassette
- Ellington Concert Part 2, 1976-1995; cuid20732 (Box 9, Audiocassette 103)
  [Side A] Jenkins Ellington Conc. [Side B] Abrams Audiocassette IRISH 261 C60
- Night in Fata Morgana, 1982-1995; cuid20733 (Box 9, Audiocassette 104)
  ©1982 Virginia A. Boyle 9241 S. Damen Chicago, Il. 60620 (312) 233-2330 (312) 281-9075 Audiocassette
- Billie Holiday b/w Langston Hughes, 1976-1995; cuid20734 (Box 9, Audiocassette 104A)
  [Side A] Billie Holiday in rehearsal w/ Jimmy Rowles, piano, and Artie Shapiro, bass; Las Vegas 1954 [Side B] Langston Hughes w/ Charles Mingus ""Weary Blues"" Audiocassette TDK D-90 [May include material used in subsequent composition]
- The World Sax Quartet - Reel 1 of 4, 1981-1995; cuid20735 (Box 10, Quarter inch audio reel 105)
  Hopkins Center, Dartmough College; May 5, 1981 Recorder: SC-280 Stereo, Halftrack, 7 1/2 IPS Scotch RB-1/4-7 [On reel: ""Seven""] 1/4-inch Audio Reel
- The World Sax Quartet - Reel 2 of 4, 1981-1995; cuid20736 (Box 8, Quarter inch audio reel 106)
  Hopkins Center, Dartmough College; May 5, 1981 Recorder: SC-280 Stereo, Halftrack, 7 1/2 IPS Scotch RB-1/4-7 [On reel: ""I""] 1/4-inch Audio Reel
- The World Sax Quartet - Reel 3 of 4, 1981-1995; cuid20737 (Box 8, Quarter inch audio reel 107)